Pamela Digby Churchill Hayward Harriman Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Part II: Event File, 1978-1992 (Box II:205-II:262)
  - 1988
    - Apr. 20, annual political action committee dinner
      - Contributions, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:244)
      - Correspondence, (2 folders)
      - Lists
      - Photographs
      - Planning, (2 folders)
      - Press, (2 folders) (Box II:245)
      - Seating, (2 folders)
      - Speeches
    - May 21, Al Gore fund-raiser at Willow Oaks
      - Contributions
      - Correspondence
      - Lists
      - Planning
    - May 24, Democratic Senatorial Campaign Committee reception (Box II:246)
    - June 26, Charles S. Robb fund-raiser, (2 folders)
    - July 13, Michael S. Dukakis dinner
    - July 18, Donald Marron dinner
    - July 18-21, Democratic National Convention
      - Correspondence
      - Credentials
      - Delegates' binder, (4 folders)
      - Interviews (Box II:247)
      - Invitations
      - Photograph
      - Planning
      - Press, (3 folders)
      - Printed matter, (2 folders)
      - Schedules
    - Sept. 8, New York, N.Y., luncheon for Pamela Harriman (Box II:248)
    - Sept. 29, Democratic Senatorial Campaign Committee fall dinner
      - Contributions, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence, (2 folders)
      - Lists, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:249)
      - Planning, (3 folders)
      - Press
      - Seating, (2 folders)
      - Speeches
    - Nov. 8, election night, (2 folders) (Box II:250)
    - Miscellaneous events, (2 folders)
  - 1989
    - Feb. 27
      - Democratic Governors' Association annual dinner
      - National Policy Forum
    - Mar. 3-5, 1990 incumbent campaign planning weekend, (3 folders)
    - Mar. 9-11, Democratic Leadership Council annual conference (Box II:251)
    - Apr. 18, National Policy Forum
    - May 4, International Ladies Garment Workers Union roast
    - May 5-7, Democratic Senatorial Campaign Committee Kentucky Derby weekend
    - May 22, National Policy Forum
    - June 12, political action committee annual dinner
      - Call lists
      - Correspondence, (3 folders)
      - Invitations and pledges, (1 folder) (Box II:252)
      - Photographs
      - Planning, (2 folders)
      - Press
      - Receipts
      - Seating
      - Speeches
    - July 26, Democratic Senatorial Campaign Committee fall dinner kick-off, (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box II:253)
    - Aug. 1-3, Democratic Senatorial Campaign Committee industry breakfast, (2 folders)
    - Sept. 11, Senate administrative assistants' reception
    - Sept. 27, Democratic Senatorial Campaign Committee fall dinner
      - California planning trip
      - Contribution history, (2 folders) (Box II:254)
      - Contributions, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence, (2 folders)
      - Federal Election Commission report
      - Lists (Box II:255)
      - New York meeting
      - Nightcap reception
      - Planning, (3 folders)
      - Press
      - Seating, (3 folders)
      - Simon, Paul (1928-2003), luncheon (Box II:256)
      - Speeches
    - Oct. 5, Mary Sue Terry reception
    - Oct. 13-15, Democratic Senatorial Campaign Committee, Middleburg, Va., event
    - Dec. 12, New York luncheon
    - Miscellaneous events
  - 1990
    - Jan. 22, political action committee dinner
    - Mar. 8, Thomas Daschle and Richard A. Gephardt issue evening
    - May 18, People for the American Way fund-raiser
    - June 21, Democratic Decade brunch
    - June 30, Charles S. Robb reception
    - Sept. 12, Harvey Gnatt reception
    - Sept. 17, Ann Richards reception (Box II:257)
    - Sept. 18, Tony Celebrezze reception
    - Sept. 27, Daniel Akaka reception
    - Oct. 2
      - Blanchard, James J., luncheon
      - Brown, Kathleen, reception
    - Oct. 11, speaker's event
    - Oct. 16, Robert Casey reception
    - Oct. 30, Thomas S. Foley reception
    - Oct. 31, Sharon Pratt Dixon reception
    - Miscellaneous events
  - 1991
    - May 22, Clark M. Clifford reception
    - June 13-14, Democratic summit, (3 folders)
    - Nov. 7, Jim Hunt reception (Box II:258)
    - Nov. 20, White House Fellows reception
    - Miscellaneous events
  - 1992
    - Mar. 31, Terry Sanford event
    - Apr. 29, small dinner, 3038 "N" Street, N.W., Washington, D.C.
    - June 24, Link Up America
    - July 12, Robert S. Strauss breakfast, (2 folders)
    - July 16, Victory '92 celebration, (2 folders)
    - Aug. 20, Richard Stallings fund-raiser
    - Sept. 12, fund-raiser for Bill Clinton and Al Gore, Middleburg, Va.
      - Accommodations
      - Attendance, (2 folders) (Box II:259)
      - Contributions, (3 folders)
      - Correspondence, (2 folders)
      - Expenses
      - Planning, (4 folders) (Box II:260)
      - Press
      - Seating
      - Speeches
      - Working files, (1 folder); (6 folder) (Box II:261)
    - Sept. 16, Dale Bumpers fund-raiser (Box II:262)
    - Oct. 25, annual harvest dinner
    - Oct. 26, Steny Hoyer fund-raiser
    - Nov. 2, election night, (2 folders)
    - Nov. 17, Robert S. Strauss dinner
    - Nov. 19, buffet dinner for Bill Clinton, (2 folders)
    - Dec. 3, Ronald Harmon Brown dinner
  - Unidentified events, undated
- Part II: Lists, 1974-1993 (Box II:262-II:310)
  Lists of political officeholders and candidates, political fund-raising contributors, labor unions and officials, political action committees, lobbyists, organizational and institutional board members, professional groups, corporate leaders, and other categories, most of which were acquired by the Democrats for the 80's from other sources, but some of which are described as "Harriman contacts" or in-house lists.
  Arranged alphabetically by topical headings used by the Democrats for the 80's.
  - "33" Club, undated (Box II:262)
  - Adams, Brock, undated
  - Addabbo, Joseph P. 1981-1982 (Box II:263)
  - Adelman, Clifford, 1981
  - Administration officials committee, circa 1981
  - Aerospace companies, 1984
  - Agricultural and Dairy Educational Political Trust Co., 1980
  - Almanac of American Politics, undated
  - Ambassadors, undated
  - Aspin, Les, 1980
  - Baililes, Gerald L., 1985
  - Barry, Marion, 1982, (2 folders)
  - Biden, Joseph R.
    - Comprehensive District of Columbia representatives list, 1978
    - General, 1984
  - Biden, Joseph R., and Daniel K. Inouye See Part II: Oversize
  - Bradley, Bill, 1979-1985, undated See also Part II: Oversize (Box II:264)
  - Breaux, John, 1986
  - Bumpers, Dale, 1985
  - Business Executives for National Security, 1985
  - Business-Government Relations Council, 1979
  - Byrd, Robert C., undated
  - Cabinet secretaries, 1981
  - California
    - Democratic National Committee donor list, circa 1985, (2 folders)
    - General
      - 1977-1982, (2 folders)
      - 1983-1985, undated, (3 folders) (Box II:265)
    - Harriman contacts, 1983
  - Call lists, assorted, 1979-1981
  - Candidate receipts and expenditures by state and district, 1981
  - Cannon, Howard
    - Communications reception, 1981
    - District of Columbia lobbyists, 1981, (2 folders)
  - Carter/Mondale Presidential Committee, 1979 (Box II:266)
  - Celebrities, undated
  - Church, Frank, 1980
  - Clifford, Clark M., undated
  - Committee of Americans for Canal Treaties, 1978
  - Communications, 1985-1987, undated
  - Congressional
    - Dinners, 1976-1985 See also Part II: Oversize
    - Hill professionals, undated
    - Hill staffers, 1981-1986
    - House of Representatives, 1981-1985, undated
    - House of Representatives and Senate, 1981-1983
    - Senate, 1978-1992, (2 folders) (Box II:267)
    - Senate consultants, 1980-1982
  - Connecticut
    - General, 1980
    - Harriman contacts, 1983
  - Corporate VIPs, undated
  - Cranston, Alan, 1985-1986
  - Cuomo, Mario M., 1983-1985
  - Current corporate list, 1986
  - Daschle, Thomas, 1986
  - Defense, 1983-1985, (2 folders)
  - Dellums, Ronald V., and Sophie Englehard, 1988 (Box II:268)
  - Democratic Business/Association Forum, undated
  - Democratic Computer Resources Network database, 1990
  - Democratic Congressional Campaign Committee, 1986-1989
  - Democratic elected officials, 1981, undated
  - Democratic Governors' Association, 1985-1992
  - Democratic House and Senate Council
    - 1979-1983, (2 folders)
    - 1991 (Box II:269)
  - Democratic Leadership Council, undated
  - Democratic National Committee
    - Aggregate donor list, 1983, (5 folders) (Box II:270)
    - Business Council, 1979-1990, undated, (3 folders) (Box II:271)
    - Candidates list, undated
    - General, 1984-1990
    - National Finance Council
      - 1978
      - 1980-1982, (4 folders) (Box II:272)
      - 1983, (1 folder) (Box II:273)
      - 1984-1985
    - Trustees, 1993
  - Democratic Senatorial Campaign Committee See also Part II: Oversize
    - 1981-1985, (3 folders)
    - 1985-1986, (4 folders) (Box II:274)
    - 1988-1990, (6 folders) (Box II:275)
    - Undated (Box II:276)
  - Democratic state and party officials, 1981-1989
  - Democratic traditional contributors, 1981
  - Democratic women, 1981
  - Democrats for the 80's
    - Additions to database, 1982
    - Address lists See Part II: Oversize
    - Full database listing, 1988, (2 folders)
    - Fund-raising master galley See Part II: Oversize (Box II:277)
    - Galley lists See Part II: Oversize
    - High donors See Part II: Oversize
    - Not donors See Part II: Oversize
    - Small donors See Part II: Oversize
    - State-by-state run See Part II: Oversize
    - VIP tapes, 1985-1986 See also Part II: Oversize, (2 folders)
    - Unidentified See Part II: Oversize
  - Dinkins, David, 1989
  - District of Columbia
    - General, 1981-1992, undated, (2 folders)
    - Harriman contacts, 1983, (2 folders) (Box II:278)
    - Mayoral election, 1982, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:279)
    - Metropolitan area, 1983, 1990-1992, (3 folders)
    - Political donations, Democratic and Republican See Part II: Oversize
  - Dixon, Alan J., undated
  - Dodd, Christopher J., 1979-1985 See also Part II: Oversize
  - Doggett, Lloyd, 1984
  - Dwoskin, [Albert J.?], event, 1992
  - Evans, John V., 1985 (Box II:280)
  - Feinstein, Diane, 1991-1992
  - Florida
    - General, 1985
    - Harriman contacts, 1983, undated
  - Foley, Thomas S.
    - National donor list, 1981, (3 folders)
    - New York luncheon, undated
  - Forbes magazine, 1982-1985
  - Fortune 500
    - 1979
    - 1980-1982 (Box II:281)
  - Friendly, Pie, 1980
  - Fund-raising
    - Database file, 1985
    - General, 1985-1991, undated, (2 folders)
    - "Important lists"
      - Democratic National Committee, 1988
      - Democratic Senatorial Campaign Committee, 1988
      - General, 1985-1988, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box II:282)
      - Labor, 1987-1988
    - VIP, 1982-1992, (2 folders)
  - Georgia, Harriman contacts, 1983
  - Glenn, John
    - 1976-1983, (2 folders)
    - 1983, (3 folders) (Box II:283)
  - Gore, Al
    - Fund-raising lists from various sources, 1986-1988, (2 folders) (Box II:284)
    - Virginia-West Virginia contributors, 1992
  - Gore, Al, and John D. Rockefeller, IV See Part II: Oversize
  - Government relations representatives, 1980-1985, (2 folders)
  - Governors, 1981-1982
  - Green Door Benefit Committee, undated
  - Haley, Riitta, rolodex, undated, (1 folder) (Box II:285)
  - Harkin, Tom, New York lists, 1984-1989
  - Harriman fund-raiser attendees, undated
  - Harris, Pat, 1982
  - Hart, Gary, 1983-1985
  - Hawkins, Paula, political action committee contributions, 1986
  - Hightower, Jim, 1981
  - Hollings, Ernest F. ("Fritz"), 1983
  - Holtzman, Elizabeth, 1980-1989
  - Howard, James J., 1981-1982, (2 folders)
  - Howard, Janet A., listing, 1980, (5 folders) (Box II:286)
  - Hoyer, Steny H., undated
  - Illinois (Box II:287)
    - General, 1979-1990
    - Harriman contacts, 1983
  - Independent Action, 1986
  - Individual dinner contributors (1976-1980), 1981, (4 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:288)
  - Inouye, Daniel K., 1985-1986 See also Part II: Oversize, (2 folders)
  - Interest groups, undated
  - Jackson, Michael C., 1982
  - Jewish, 1981-1986, (2 folders)
  - Johnston, Bennett, undated
  - Jones, James R., 1985
  - Kennedy, Edward M., 1980-1986 See also Part II: Oversize
  - Key telephone numbers, 1985
  - Kling, S. Lee, 1979
  - Koch, Edward, 1989 (Box II:289)
  - Labor
    - 1979-1985, (6 folders)
    - 1985-1991, undated, (5 folders) (Box II:290)
  - Lansburgh, Therese W., 1982-1983
  - Latham and Watkins, 1988
  - Lawyers, undated (Box II:291)
  - Leahy, Patrick J., 1985-1986
  - Letter recipients
    - Five-hundred-dollar contributor letter, undated
    - Strauss-Clifford-Kling letter, 1984
  - Lobbyists, undated
  - Long, Russell B. See Part II: Oversize
  - Louisiana, undated
  - Lundine, Stan, 1986
  - Mailing lists, circa 1981
  - Maryland
    - General, 1978
    - Harriman contacts, 1983
    - Lobbyists, 1983
  - Massachusetts, Harriman contacts, 1983 (Box II:292)
  - Master list, 1982
  - Mayors, 1981-1990, undated, (2 folders)
  - Metzenbaum, Howard M., 1982
  - Miscellaneous, 1979-1990 See also Part II: Oversize
  - Mississippi, undated
  - Moffett, George, 1979, undated
  - Mondale, Walter F.
    - 1983, (2 folders)
    - Undated (Box II:293)
  - Multi-state
    - General, 1983-1984
    - Harriman contacts
      - 1981-1982, (2 folders)
      - 1983, (2 folders) (Box II:294)
    - Harriman project, 1982, (2 folders) (Box II:295)
  - Muskie, Edmund S., 1981
  - Nathan, Robert, 1984
  - National Democratic Club, undated
  - National Democratic Institute awards and press list, 1986
  - Nelson, Gaylord, 1979
  - New Jersey, Harriman contacts, 1983 (Box II:296)
  - New York
    - Donor list, 1986
    - General
      - 1974-1984, (3 folders)
      - 1985-1989, (5 folders) (Box II:297)
      - 1989-1990, undated, (3 folders) (Box II:298)
    - Harriman contacts, 1983-1984, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:299)
  - Newsletter address lists, 1982-1988, undated, (3 folders)
  - Nonprofit groups and public interest law, 1981
  - Nunn, Sam See Part II: Oversize
  - Ohio
    - General, 1975-1981
    - Harriman contacts, 1983
  - Oil and gas companies, 1982 (Box II:300)
  - Op-ed article mailing list, undated
  - Pennsylvania
    - General, undated
    - Harriman contacts, 1983
  - Pharmaceutical lobbyists, 1979
  - Phone bank, undated
  - Political action committees
    - Business, 1979-1981, (2 folders)
    - Business and progressive, 1985
    - By organization, 1979
    - Donating over five-hundred dollars, 1988
    - Donating to Democratic Senate candidates, 1989 (Box II:301)
    - Donating twenty-five percent or more to Democrats, 1986
    - Federal Election Commission
      - 1981-1985, (3 folders)
      - 1989 (Box II:302)
    - General, 1980-1992, undated, (5 folders)
    - Generic list, undated (Box II:303)
    - Issue-oriented, undated
    - Labor, progressive, and Israel, 1986-1990
  - Political Christmas card address list (1983), 1982-1983
  - Pollin, Irene, 1982
  - Pollsters, 1991, undated
  - Potomac Group, 1982-1983
  - Presidential contributions, 1988
  - Press (Box II:304)
    - Addressed envelopes, undated
    - General, 1981-1985, undated, (2 folders)
    - VIP and personal, 1987, undated
  - Republican Senate-House Dinner Committee, 1981 (Box II:305)
  - Rockefeller, John D., IV, 1983-1984, undated
  - Rockefeller University, New York, N.Y., board of trustees, undated
  - Rolodexes, photocopies, undated
    - Brown, (2 folders)
    - Green
    - Small black (Box II:306)
  - Sanford, Terry
    - Individuals, 1992
    - Political action committees, 1992
  - Simon, Paul (1928-2003), 1983-1985 See also Part II: Oversize
  - Small donors
    - General, 1990, undated
    - Harriman contacts, 1985
  - Sports, 1981-1982
  - Tax coalitions, undated
  - Telephone source, 1985, undated
  - Texas
    - General, 1978-1983, undated, (2 folders)
    - Harriman contacts, 1982-1983 (Box II:307)
  - Trade, undated
  - U.S. Senate Democratic Leadership Circle, 1985
  - VIPs, 1985, undated, (3 folders)
  - Virginia
    - General, 1986
    - Harriman contacts, 1983
    - Registered lobbyists, 1983
  - West Virginia and Virginia, 1992 (Box II:308)
  - White House, 1981
  - White House lists of key Americans, 1978-1979
  - White House Preservation Fund, 1979
  - Wilder, Douglas, 1992, undated
  - Williams, J. D., District of Columbia representatives list, 1979
  - Women executives, 1981
  - Women's Information Network directory, undated
  - Wright, Jim, 1979, 1986, (2 folders)
  - Yates, Sidney R., 1990-1992
  - Young Ideas, Inc., undated
  - Unidentified (Box II:309)
    - 1980-1992, (2 folders)
    - Undated, (4 folders); (3 folders) (Box II:310)
- Part II: Digital Files, 1982-1990 (Box II:DF)
  Fund-raising, event, and congratulatory letters sent; internal memoranda; lists of names and addresses; lists of political candidates and races; contributor and contribution databases; draft newsletters, press releases, speeches, and talking-points; transcript of a CSPAN interview; biographies of Harriman, and financial reports. The 1,142 files were received on thirty-nine 5.25" floppy disks. Most of them were created with WordPerfect and dBase software programs. Each disk was assigned a unique digital ID number. Access to digital content is available onsite only in the Manuscript Reading Room and requires advance notice. Use the digital ID number to request access copies of the files.
  Arranged as received and listed chronologically.
  - 1982, "Fact2" list of names and addresses, probably relating to the Democratic Fact Book, mss84292_117_077 (Box II: DF)
  - 1985
    - Contributor database, mss84292_117_069
    - Financial reports, miscellaneous, mss84292_117_003; mss84292_117_004
    - Fund-raising and event letters sent and internal memoranda, mss84292_117_041; mss84292_117_057
  - 1986-1987
    - Backed-up WordPerfect documents from staff member Joan Shaffer's computer
      - A-D, mss84292_117_018
      - D-J, mss84292_117_019
      - J-P, mss84292_117_020
      - Q-W, mss84292_117_021
      - X-Z, and miscellaneous, mss84292_117_022
    - Fund-raising and event letters sent; internal memoranda; lists of names and addresses; lists of donors; lists of political candidates and races; election congratulatory letters; draft speeches, newsletters, press releases, and talking points; transcript of a CSPAN interview; satellite communications files; and typescript of Winston Churchill's The Dream, mss84292_117_009; mss84292_117_010; mss84292_117_011; mss84292_117_012; mss84292_117_013; mss84292_117_014; mss84292_117_015; mss84292_117_067
  - 1987 (Box II: DF)
    - Contributors and 1986 contributions
      - Backup of database, mss84292_117_031; mss84292_117_032; mss84292_117_033; mss84292_117_034; mss84292_117_035; mss84292_117_036
      - Miscellaneous files, mss84292_117_029; mss84292_117_030
  - 1987-1989, backup of computer files, A-E, including fund-raising and event letters sent, internal memoranda, talking points for interviews and meetings, draft press releases, biographies of Harriman, election night lists, and files relating to the annual dinner, National Polling Project, and satellite communications projects
    - A-D, mss84292_117_016
    - D-E, mss84292_117_017
  - 1990, largely files relating to the Party of the Decade, Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts, Washington, D.C., mss84292_117_064; mss84292_117_065; mss84292_117_066; mss84292_117_091; mss84292_117_095; mss84292_117_099; mss84292_117_100; mss84292_117_105
  - Undated, manuscript on tax policy, mss84292_117_070
- Part II: Oversize, 1976-1988 (Box II:OV 1-II:OV 19)
  Card files, a financial ledger, posters, and lists.
  - Part II: Subject File (Box II:OV 1)
    - Democratic National Convention
      - 1984, San Francisco, Calif.
        - Site selection
          - Washington, D.C., bid (Container II:29)
    - Dukakis, Michael S., 1988 (Container II:39)
    - LaRouche, Lyndon H., undated (Container II:66)
  - Part II: Administrative File (Box II:OV 2)
    - Contributors
      - Card file, 1979-1980 (Container II:100)
        - A-B
        - C-E (Box II:OV 3)
        - F-I (Box II:OV 4)
        - J-M (Box II:OV 5)
        - N-S (Box II:OV 6)
        - S-Z (Box II:OV 7)
    - Financial ledgers, 1981-1982 (Container II:109) (Box II:OV 8)
  - Part II: Lists (Box II:OV 9)
    - Biden, Joseph R., and Daniel K. Inouye, 1983-1986 (Container II:263)
    - Bradley, Bill, 1979-1985 (Container II:264)
    - Congressional
      - Dinners (Container II:266)
        - 1976-1978
        - 1978-1979, (3 folders) (Box II:OV 10)
    - Democratic Senatorial Campaign Committee, 1981-1985 (Container II:273)
    - Democrats for the 80's
      - Address lists, 1985 (Container II:276), (2 folders) (Box II:OV 11)
      - Fund-raising master galley, 1986, (2 folders) (Container II:277)
      - Galley lists (Container II:277) (Box II:OV 12)
        - 1985, (4 folders)
        - 1986, (2 folders) (Box II:OV 13)
      - High donors, 1983 (Container II:277)
      - Not donors, 1985 (Container II:277)
      - Small donors, 1985 (Container II:277), (1 folder); (4 folders) (Box II:OV 14)
      - State-by-state run, 1983, (2 folders) (Box II:OV 15)
      - VIP tape, 1986, (2 folders) (Container II:277)
      - Unidentified, undated (Container II:277) (Box II:OV 16)
    - District of Columbia political donations, Democratic and Republican, 1982 (Container II:279)
    - Dodd, Christopher J., 1979-1980 (Container II:279)
    - Gore, Al, and John D. Rockefeller, IV, 1983-1984 (Container II:284) (Box II:OV 17)
    - Inouye, Daniel K., 1985-1986 (Container II:288)
    - Kennedy, Edward M., 1980-1981, (3 folders)(Container II:288)
    - Long, Russell B., 1985 (Container II:291) (Box II:OV 18)
    - Miscellaneous, 1979-1987, (5 folders) (Container II:292)
    - Nunn, Sam, 1983-1985 (Container II:299) (Box II:OV 19)
    - Simon, Paul (1928-2003), 1983-1984 (Container II:306)